Contact

- ★ Jordan, Amman
- **** 00962798000023
- rakanaljamal@gmail.com
- in rakan-aljamal-7844ab181
- github.com/RakanAljamal
- hackerrank.com/rakanaljamal

Profile

Software Engineer who has been interested in Software Development since I finished my high school.

Diligent, Creative and able to works in a fully agile environment

Have the desire to keep learning anything related to modern development

Skills

Javascript React NodeJS **Typescript** NextJS Linux Docker Git MongoDB MySQL AWS *iQuery* Spring Java Maven Algorithms **Data Structures** GraphQL



RAKAN ALJAMAL

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Summary

Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in Design, Development and Implementation of **Web and Client/Server development**.

Delightful experience developing and maintaing front-end applications.using ReactJS, NextJS and GraphQL.

Decent experience in NodeJS when dealing with RDBMS or NOSQL

My previous work was mainly in **Java** using **J2EE**, **Restful Web Services**, **Spring**.

Alongside a good experience in **cloud development** mainly in **AWS** using **Dokcer Contianer** or **LINUX**.

Experience

Software Engineer

Sajilni | 2020 - 2021

- Manage the whole application infrastructure which uses JQuery as the front-end, JAVA (Spring) as the back-end. AWS as the Cloud Provider.
- Develop a micro-services to handle **Auth, Notifications** and **Metadata** for a *virtual event-management system*.

Software Engineer

Aspire (Weightwatchers) | 2021 - Present

- Manage a cutting-edge Studio finder application which deals with maps, locations and geocodes, written in NextJS (React) for SSO, SSR and optimization.
- Worked on a NodeJS API that fetch locations and geocodes as service for the **Studio finder** application.
- Deployment process was managed by running a **Docker** container automated by GitHub

Education

UNIVERSITY OF JORDAN
 Jordan, Amman | 2015 - 2019
 Computer Science